<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on SmokeFree Waiheke</title><link>//www.smokefreewaiheke.org.nz/post/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on SmokeFree Waiheke</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Jul 2021 18:23:13 +1200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//www.smokefreewaiheke.org.nz/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Smoke drift is not harmless</title><link>//www.smokefreewaiheke.org.nz/post/smoke-drift-is-not-harmless/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jul 2021 18:23:13 +1200</pubDate><guid>//www.smokefreewaiheke.org.nz/post/smoke-drift-is-not-harmless/</guid><description>Make it the responsibility of the smoker to prevent smoke drift at all times and places There is no safe level of second hand smoke exposure. In New Zealand, second hand smoke is considered to contribute to over 350 deaths per year.
If you can smell tobacco smoke it is harming you It can trigger premature heart attack, hypertension, stroke and respiratory problems It doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter if you are outside It doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter if you are metres away Sign the petition to parliament: https://www.</description></item><item><title>Do you mind if I smoke?</title><link>//www.smokefreewaiheke.org.nz/post/do-you-mind/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 10:26:37 +1200</pubDate><guid>//www.smokefreewaiheke.org.nz/post/do-you-mind/</guid><description>This is a confrontation masked as a polite question. The more accurate question is, &amp;ldquo;Do you mind if I expose you to another load of arsenic and other toxins along with the nicotine, knowing that you will probably experience more forced tobacco smoke exposure today and every other day just going about your daily life, which contributes to the high statistics of preventable smoke-related deaths and diseases?&amp;quot; Or more succinctly, &amp;ldquo;Do you mind if I contribute to shortening your life?</description></item><item><title>You are Not Alone</title><link>//www.smokefreewaiheke.org.nz/post/not-alone/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 18:26:37 +1200</pubDate><guid>//www.smokefreewaiheke.org.nz/post/not-alone/</guid><description>Being taken seriously It seems the first hurdle that people affected by SHS encounter is various forms of denial. Oh so you can smell my tobacco smoke, don&amp;rsquo;t worry its: just vapour, not dangerous, too dilute to cause a problem, doesn&amp;rsquo;t affect you, will pass by in a moment. Or you can - always move away, close a window, turn on a fan etc. etc.
There&amp;rsquo;s a prevalent idea that only long term exposure is a risk factor.</description></item></channel></rss>